Gary!
加里！
- Meow.
- Gary?
- 喵。
- 加里？
Where are you, Gere-bear?
基尔熊，你在哪里？
Meow.
喵。
- Meow.
- Gary!
- 喵。
- 加里！
Gary!
加里！
How did you get up there,
you silly snail?
你是怎么爬上去的，
你这个傻蜗牛？
Come on. Jump!
快点。跳！
Jumpity-jump-jump-jump!
跳-跳-跳-跳！
Meow.
喵。
Huh.
呵呵。
"In case of pet in tree,
pull down."
“如果宠物在树上，
拉下来。”
All right.
好的。
Did someone call
the fire department?
有人打电话吗
消防部门？
Wow.
哇。
Step aside, citizen.
公民，靠边站吧。
Ladder. First aid. Blanket.
梯子。急救。毯子。
Let's hustle, people. Hustle!
让我们加油吧，人们。喧嚣！
Okay.
好的。
Here I come.
我来了。
Yeah.
是的。
You're safe now, sonny.
你现在安全了，儿子。
Almost there.
快到了。
Meow. Meow.
喵。喵。
Thank you for rescuing
my little Gare bear.
谢谢你的救命之恩
我的小车站熊。
Hey, Larry.
嘿，拉里。
I'd like to be a firefighter.
我想成为一名消防员。
Can I be one, please?
Can I please?
请问我可以成为其中一员吗？
我可以吗？
Sorry, SpongeBob.
对不起，海绵宝宝。
There are no openings
at this time.
没有空缺
此时。
I think I shattered
my skeleton.
我想我崩溃了
我的骷髅。
Again.
再次。
Ooh. I may regret this
哦。我可能会后悔这一点
but it looks like
we do have an opening.
但看起来像
我们确实有一个空缺。
See you at the firehouse,
I guess.
消防站见
我猜。
The next day.
第二天。
Gahhoydin!
加霍伊丁！
You okay there, SpongeBob?
你还好吗，海绵宝宝？
Oh, yeah. Haha.
Reporting for duty!
哦，是的。哈哈。
到岗报到！
Meow. Meow--
喵。喵——
I brought my own snail-mation!
我带来了我自己的蜗牛伴侣！
Okay.
好的。
Well, welcome
to the Bikini Bottom
嗯，欢迎
到比基尼底部
Volunteer Fire Department!
志愿消防队！
Oh, yeah! Where's the fire?
Where's the fire?
哦，是啊！火在哪里？
火在哪里？
I'm gonna fight it!
我要对抗它！
Where is it? Where? Where?
它在哪里？在哪里？在哪里？
Yep. I'm regretting it.
是的。我很后悔。
Here we keep the hoses
that extinguish the fires.
我们把软管放在这里
来扑灭大火。
Well, they sure extinguished
my thirst!
好吧，他们确实熄灭了
我的渴！
Upstairs.
楼上。
This is the bunk room
where we rest up between fires.
这是双层床房
我们在火灾之间休息的地方。
Ooh! Should I pick a bunk?
哦！我应该选择双层床吗？
No, too soft.
Too hard.
不行，太软了。
太难了。
Tutu?
图图？
Too lumpy. Whoa.
太块了。哇哦。
Patrick!
帕特里克！
I'm gonna start fires!
我要放火了！
Put out fires.
We put out fires.
扑灭大火。
我们扑灭了大火。
If you say so.
如果你这么说的话。
Rookie,
meet your fellow volunteer,
菜鸟，
认识你的志愿者同伴，
Charmed, I'm sure.
我确信，很着迷。
My pleasure. You look familiar.
我的荣幸。你看起来很熟悉。
Hey! What's that?
嘿！那是什么？
The First Fire?
第一场火灾？
Wow!
哇！
Is this the first fire
in the history of forever?
这是第一次火灾吗
在历史上永远？
No. It's the first fire
we ever got called to.
不，这是第一场火灾
我们曾经被叫过。
We keep it as a memento.
我们把它留作纪念。
Hey! Fire poles!
嘿！火柱！
Wow! Can we slide
down the poles?
哇！我们可以滑吗
沿着两极？
Hold on there, greenhorns.
等等，新手们。
You need to learn
which one to use.
你需要学习
使用哪一个。
This is the pole
to the fire boat.
这是杆子
到消防船。
This one's to the kitchen.
这是去厨房的。
It's slippery.
很滑。
It's buttered.
是涂了黄油的
This pole goes to the bathroom.
这根杆子通向浴室。
That's my ride.
这就是我的旅程。
Ooh. Where does this pole go?
哦。这根柱子去哪儿了？
Oh, that one's the mystery pole.
哦，那是神秘的柱子。
It never goes
to the same place twice.
它永远不会过去
去同一个地方两次。
I love a mystery!
我喜欢神秘！
- Yay!
- No! Wait!
- 耶！
- 不！等待！
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
哇！哇！哇！哇！
How do you stop
this crazy thing?
你怎么停下来
这疯狂的事？
Hit the brakes!
踩刹车！
No! No! Huh?
不！不！啊？
Do you still love a mystery?
你还喜欢神秘吗？
Not so much these days.
这些天不那么多了。
All right. Line up!
好的。排队！
Squidward!
章鱼哥！
You volunteered too?
你也是自愿的吗？
Not me. Mr. Krabs.
不是我。蟹老板。
He was court-mandated for this
他因此被法庭责令
but sent me in his stead.
但派我代替他。
I'm a proxy.
我是代理人。
Ooh. Hi, proxy.
I'm boxy.
哦。你好，代理。
我是四四方方的。
I'm foxy.
我很狡猾。
Well, then I'm an escapee.
好吧，那我就是逃犯了。
All right. Listen up!
好的。听着！
This is the training area.
这是训练区。
The reason why
there are three of you
原因是
你们三个人
is because one Old Man Walker
是因为一位沃克老人
is worth three good men.
抵得上三个好男人。
And I couldn't find
three good men
而我却找不到
三个好男人
so I got you...
所以我得到了你...
Your training starts now!
你的训练现在开始！
And hopefully ends
at some point.
并希望结束
在某个时刻。
First up, fire hose skills.
首先，消防水带技能。
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
哇！哇！哇！
Help! Fire!
帮助！火！
Someone save my baby!
谁来救救我的宝贝吧！
We'll save your baby!
我们会救你的孩子的！
Careful, SpongeBob. Slowly.
小心点，海绵宝宝。慢慢地。
Save my baby!
救救我的宝贝！
- Mama!
- What she said!
- 妈妈！
- 她说什么！
Oh.
哦。
I saved the baby, chief.
我救了孩子，长官。
And what about the mother?
那么母亲呢？
The-the mother?
那——母亲？
The mother!
母亲！
Congratulations, men.
恭喜你们，伙计们。
You passed your training.
你通过了训练。
- Yeah!
- Woohoo!
- 是的！
- 哇哦！
Kill me now.
现在就杀了我吧。
You're all
volunteer firefighters.
你们都是
志愿消防员。
Huzzah.
万岁。
Huh?
啊？
Sorry, Squidward. We're out of
fire helmets and walkie talkies.
对不起，章鱼哥。我们已经没了
消防头盔和对讲机。
But, um...
但是，嗯...
Here's some stuff left over
from our last party.
这是剩下的一些东西
从我们上次聚会开始。
Another pet in a tree?
树上还有一只宠物？
I've got better things to do.
我还有更重要的事情要做。
Like sleep. Hmm?
就像睡觉一样。唔？
Look alive, men!
看起来还活着，伙计们！
You've got your
very first assignment!
你有你的
第一个作业！
It's Spot!
He's stuck in the tree!
是现货！
他被困在树上了！
Wow.
哇。
What was I thinking?
It's SpongeBob!
我在想什么？
这是海绵宝宝！
Never mind. Sorry to bother you.
没关系。很抱歉打扰你。
He can stay in the tree.
他可以留在树上。
Step aside, citizen.
公民，靠边站吧。
Ladder. First aid. Blanket!
梯子。急救。毯子！
Hustle, people!
喧嚣，人们！
Yeah, this is firefighter
SpongeBob to Chief Larry.
是的，这是消防员
海绵宝宝对拉里酋长说。
The rescue subject just
regurgitated all over Patrick.
救援对象刚刚
帕特里克浑身反流。
Squidward got hurled on too.
章鱼哥也被扔了。
Keep up the good work.
继续做好工作。
Come on, boy.
来吧，男孩。
Jump!
跳！
Meow.
喵。
Good snail-mation!
好蜗牛！
Huh?
啊？
Do you hear that?
你听到了吗？
There's a fire somewhere!
某处着火了！
A real fire!
真正的火！
Hustle!
喧嚣！
Huh?
啊？
Oh, uh, Squidward.
The siren is broken.
哦，呃，章鱼哥。
警笛坏了。
Could you, uh, [honks].
你可以吗，呃，[喇叭]。
Watch where you're going, bozo!
小心你要去哪里，老兄！
A fire house on fire.
一座消防屋着火了。
Talk about your cheap irony.
谈谈你的廉价讽刺。
Help!
帮助！
The First Fire escaped!
第一把火逃走了！
Save me!
救救我吧！
Okay. Jump!
好的。跳！
Whoa!
哇！
Well, that was a rip off!
好吧，那真是敲诈了！
Okay, men. Fire hose skills!
好吧，男人们。消防水带技能！
Mother of Pearl!
珍珠母！
Don't worry, you're saved!
别担心，你有救了！
Hey! You know--
嘿！你知道 -
Did somebody
need three good men?
有人吗
需要三个好男人吗？
Meow! Meow!
喵！喵！
Now, hold on in there, you kids.
现在，坚持住，孩子们。
Wow!
哇！
Ha! Didn't I tell ya
哈!我不是告诉过你吗
Old Man Walker
is worth three good men?
沃克老人
值三个好男人吗？
Hey! Where's SpongeBob?
嘿！海绵宝宝在哪里？
Yes! I saved it!
是的！我救了它！
I saved the First Fire!
我救了第一场大火！
Whoa!
哇！
I wonder if I can volunteer
for something safer.
我想知道我是否可以做志愿者
为了更安全的事情。
Medical experiments.
That sounds good.
医学实验。
听起来很好。
This is your lucky day!
这是你的幸运日！
I'm also a volunteer doctor.
我也是一名志愿医生。